

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





**Dhruvit Patel** Dhruvit Patel Featured [Immediate Joiner] Business Analyst seeking roles in Application Analyst, Product Analyst, Requirement Analysis, Incident Management, Problem Management, SDLC, Agile, Scrum, Unix, SQL, Toad, Oracle SQL, Service Now, Jira, R programming, SQL, SAP BO Current Designation: Business Analyst -IT Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 4 Month(s) Current Company: Societe Generale Notice Period: 15 Days or less Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Mumbai, Gurgaon Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Role: Business Analyst Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: business analyst,application analyst,product analyst,sdlc,agile,scrum, sql,toad,oracle sql developer,service now,jira,azure devops board,sap business object,requirement gathering,use cases,business analysis,Production

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Verified : Number | Email - id

Support, Application Support

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills

## Summary

\*\* Immediate Joiner \*\* Result oriented professional with more than 3 years of experience in Banking referential system, product support, testing, SDLC, Agile, Scrum, Application support.

Working closely with the business sponsors, project managers / product owners gathering solution requirements, business cases, etc.

Lead & engage in discussions with development teams, product owners, other technical teams in translating & implementing the user stories.

Working in agile scrum framework, organizing sprint meetings for backlog refinement, planning, daily scrums & retrospection for areas of improvements.

Collaborate and build relationship & goodwill with partners, different teams.

Experience across application Testing, Application Support, SDLC, process improvements and Agile methodologies in IT industry.

Creating user stories using Atlassian Jira tool & prioritize the backlog for delivery aligning to the roadmap.

## **Work Experience**

Societe Generale as Business Analyst -IT Aug 2017 to Till Date

Roles:

1. Business Analyst

(September 2018-Present)

Key functions: Stake-holder management, CRM, Requirement gathering Functional test, BRD, reporting, Workflow analysis and solutions, Data Analysis, UAT, Functional testing.

2. Application Support

(August 2017- August 2018)

Key Functions: Troubleshooting, Bugs identification, release support and deployments, Change/Incident/Problem management

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY

Business Analyst

Work closely with the business sponsors, project managers / product owners gathering solution requirements, business cases, etc.,

Strategize & define the product roadmap, building product backlog by understanding the vision and benefits of the business requirement

Creating user stories using Atlassian Jira tool & prioritize the backlog for delivery aligning to the roadmap Identify and raise risks, issues, assumptions, dependencies, etc. to support solution delivery

Work across different business functions & data consumers (sourcing) understanding how it's used, assess risk & impacts, identify viable technology to use

impacs, dentity wable technology to dee

## **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. Lead & engage in discussions with development teams, product owners, other technical teams in translating & implementing the user stories

Create user acceptance criteria, perform test and validate & track the planned implementations during sprint cycle Working in agile scrum framework, organizing sprint meetings for backlog refinement, planning, daily scrums & retrospection for areas of improvements

Applying good judgment in balancing and advocating the use of agile delivery concepts and business analysis tools and techniques

Collaborate and build relationship & goodwill with partners, different teams

User Acceptance Testing

Raise development bugs, bug priority assessment, high quality analysis and details on how to reproduce issues and logging defects in JIRA

Design testing plans to diagnose and resolve system exceptions & errors.

Writing and executing test cases, reporting defects and testing bugs.

Training &Mentoring

Conduct trainings and presentations for global counterparts

Responsible for training new-hires on system application and mentoring on-shore and off-shore team members

#### **KEYPROJECTS**

PRM

Business Analyst: Managed the progress of key project deliverables, designed and executed test cases. Done Gap Analysis and provided business rules to implement logic. Developed user acceptance test plans for new product functionalities.

FICOBA

Helped stakeholder to develop road map for the requirement. Implemented FTR approach to share the banking details. Worked with different teams to understand the data sourcing and technology to use in implementing the project.

**EMIR Enslavement** 

^ Back to Top

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Siddaganga Institute of Technology (SIT) in 2017

^ Back to Top

### **IT Skills**

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience UNIX, SQL Toad, Oracle SQL Developer Service NOW, JIRA Azure Devops board Excel, Tableau SAP Business Object Jenkins, GIT			
Toad, Oracle SQL Developer Service NOW, JIRA Azure Devops board Excel, Tableau SAP Business Object	Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Service NOW, JIRA Azure Devops board Excel, Tableau SAP Business Object	UNIX, SQL		
Azure Devops board  Excel, Tableau  SAP Business Object	Toad, Oracle SQL Developer		
Excel, Tableau  SAP Business Object	Service NOW, JIRA		
SAP Business Object	Azure Devops board		
•	Excel, Tableau		
Jenkins, GIT	SAP Business Object		
	Jenkins, GIT		

^ Back to Top

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Gujarati	Proficient	✓		✓

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.